Hello, Namaste, welcome to PolicyX. Here
you will find all the
information related to insurance, honest reviews of every plan available and trending in the market.
Today we will talk about the Star Health
Ashor plan. We are providing you with the most
updated version of this plan. The Star
Health Ashor insurance plan provides
continuous medical coverage for individuals and families, with
your sum insured automatically refilled
unlimited times within the policy year.
This plan offers a 20% wellness
discount on renewal premiums.
If your sum insured is 10 lakh or
more, there is no limit on room rent.
Furthermore, this plan
also covers consumer costs such as
hospitalization and an annual
health checkup.
We have seen many people commenting
asking
which plan to choose for pregnancy. This
plan is for them because the Star Health
Ashor insurance plan
also provides comprehensive coverage for pregnancy-related procedures.
This includes delivery expenses, in utero
fetal surgery, intervention assisted reproduction
treatment, and newborn baby
expenses. Meaning, if
you need medical treatment during pregnancy,
this plan
will also provide coverage for all of them.
Keep these points in mind which I am
going to tell you now. First of all, in short,
Star Assure will provide you coverage ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 2
crore. Policy tenure is one,
two, and three years. There are more than 14,000 network hospitals in this plan.
You will not need a pre-policy medical checkup
under this plan. The
waiting period for pre-aging diseases is 30 months. There is
also a payment for 36 months.
Co-payment is available for people above 60 years of age.
Now coming to the benefits, i.e. the
benefits of Star Health Assure. The first
benefit is that in this family health insurance
policy, compared to other health insurance plans,
policyholders get coverage for non-medical
items such as gloves, masks, oxygen
cylinders, armrests.  You can also claim medical expenses on a SLING. The
second
benefit of this plan is automatic restoration of sum
insured. This means that with this benefit, the
policy's sum insured will be automatically restored to 100% every time, that
too
partially or fully exhausted. The claim is
available unlimited times within the policy year. The third benefit is
no room rent capping. This means that
if your sum insured is Rs 10 lakh or more, then there is no
room limit on hospital room rent.
Policyholders can also earn a wellness discount of up to
20% on their Star Health Assure Insurance policy
on their renewal premium if they collect
more than 750 wellness points under the Star Wellness Program. The
next
benefit you will get under this plan is that
Star Health & Allied Insurance Company will pay the
cost of your preventive health checkup every year. The next benefit is cumulative
bonus, which means that the policy sum insured will
increase by 25% for every claim-free year.
This bonus can be up to a maximum of 100%. The
minimum entry age for Star Health Ashor is
18 years for an adult and 16 days for a child. The
maximum entry age is
75 years for an adult and 17 years for a child. The coverage
type is both individual and family floater.
Now, a very important part is
what will be covered in Star Health Ashor.
This plan will cover: Inpatient
hospitalization, non-medical items such as
oxygen cylinder, gloves, masks, extra
emergency, road ambulance, air ambulance, pre
and post hospitalization expenses, day
care procedures, organ donor expenses,
delivery expenses covered in uterine surgery,
interventional reproductive treatment, newborn
baby hospitalization expenses, home care
treatment, domiciliary
factory, asthma treatment, compassionate travel, repetition
of mortal remains, treatment in
valuable service provider network,
shared accommodation, AYUSH treatment, second
medical opinion, modern treatments, rehabilitation
and pain management. These were the
things covered under this plan.
What will not be covered in the Star Health Ashore policy, i.e.
exclusions, will not be covered in it:
Maternity expenses, Obesity
and weight control treatment, Treatment of alcohol or drug
addiction, Vaccination or
inoculation, Sterility and infertility
treatments and treatments
taken outside India. Apart from this, intentional
self-injury, Injury in adventure or hazardous sports,
Continental external
defects, Cosmetic or plastic surgery,
Dietary supplements and substances and
unproven treatments will also
not be covered under this policy. Talking about the initial waiting
period,
you will get an initial waiting period of 30 days in this plan. The
specific initial waiting period is
24 months. The waiting period for pre-existing diseases is
30 months for a three-year
policy tenure and 36 months for the rest, i.e.
36 months. The waiting period for delivery expenses
is 24 months. In utero fetal
surgery intimation waiting period is 24
months. Assisted reproduction  Treatment
waiting period is 24 months New born
baby cover waiting period is 12 months This was about
honest review If you want honest and
expert advice or
want to buy a health or term plan then
book your call today
You will get the link to book a call as per your time
in the description box Policy is
no spam no gimmicks till then bye-bye